

Apartment 20, St. James's Court, Echlin Street, Dublin 8

□ (+353) 89-4960-450 | ■ amukesh.mk@gmail.com | 🗖 mukeshmk | 📓 mukesh-a | 🛅 mukeshmk95 | 🕑 amukeshmk

Personal Summary _____

A Master's in Data Science student from Trinity College of Dublin, with 2 years of work experience as an Application Engineer at Oracle India, Pvt. Ltd. Highly skilled in Machine Learning, Data Analytics, and Creative Thinking. Seeking a challenging career as a Data Scientist to apply my knowledge and skills by tackling real-world issues. I am available for employment upon submission of my thesis in August 2020.

Skills

Programming: Python, Java, R, Processing, C++, C, SQL, PL/SQL

Frameworks: Scikit-Learn, Tensorflow, Flask, Spring, Hibernate, Mockito, REST

Tools & IDE's: Intellij, Eclipse, SQL Developer, Ant, Oracle12c, MySQL

Server & Version Control: Oracle Weblogic12c, git, GitHub, TortoiseHG

Education _____

Trinity College of Dublin M.Sc. IN DATA SCIENCE

aiming for 1:1

2019 - 2020

Relevant Course Work: Machine Learning, Data Analytics, Artificial Intelligence, Optimisation Algorithms for Data Analysis, Knowledge and Data Engineering, Text Analysis, Applied Statistical Modelling, Data Visualisation

Thesis: Federated Meta-Learning: Democratizing Algorithm Selection Across Disciplines and Software Libraries.

> FMLearn, an application which allows the exchange of meta-data about machine learning models and data for the purpose of meta-learned algorithm selection and configuration.

Amrita School of Engineering

CGPA: 8.37/10.0

B.Tech. In Computer Science and Engineering

2013 - 2017

Relevant Course Work: Data Structures, Design and Analysis of Algorithm, Pattern Recognition, Data Mining and Warehousing, Database Management Systems, Software Engineering

Projects _

Captcha Solver

Captcha-solver

IMAGE AND AUDIO CAPTCHA SOLVER

Oct. 2019

• Parallelized image and audio captcha solver based on TensorFlow's Convolutional Neural Networks implementation.

🗖 ban-on-awscloud9

BODY AREA NETWORK SIMULATIONR

Nov. 2019

• Implementation of Body Area Network on Amazon AWS-IoT cloud9 Instances.

Connect 4

BAN on AWS

Connect-4

GAME BASED ON ARTIFICIAL INTELLIGENCE

Jan. 2020 - May. 2020

• A multi-agent implementation of the game Connect-4 using MCTS, Minimax and Exptimax algorithms.

Sentiment Analysis

Twitter-sentiment-analysis

TWITTER SENTIMENT ANALYSIS

Jan. 2020 - May. 2020

• An opinion poll where public tweets considered as an indicator to predict the actual election results.

MUKESH ARAMBAKAM

Certifications

2016 **Machine Learning**, Stanford University, Coursera

Online Certificate

2016 Cryptography I, Stanford University, Coursera

Course Completed

Work Experience

Oracle India Private, Ltd.

APPLICATIONS ENGINEER (IC-2)

June. 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Certificate of Appreciation: For outstanding contribution to Prime Projects Product Development
- Lead the development in redesigning the security flow for the Product (Oracle Primavera Cloud), and introducing new features.
- Co-Designed and Developed an application which works across multiple platforms.
- Developed a micro-service which communicates between tenants in a Multi-Tenant Architecture.

Oracle India Private, Ltd.

APPLICATIONS DEVELOPER (IC-1)

July. 2017 - May. 2019

- Engineered multiple core features in the product Oracle Primavera Cloud.
- Optimized the product's filter framework for dynamic queries by 30% using Oracle's Query Builder framework.
- Developed an optimized search framework to retrieve data from the database using query optimization techniques.

Oracle India Private, Ltd.

GRADUATE INTERN

Jan. 2017 - June. 2017

- Worked as a Selenium Automation Engineer for Oracle Primavera.
- Briefly worked as a Quality Assurance Engineer.

Cisco Systems Private, Ltd.

Oct. 2016 - Mar. 2017

- Worked on Platform Transformation for an internal Product: Cordys Process System.
- Designed the UX, Architecture and Schema Design for the application.

Hitachi Solutions, Ltd.

INTERN July. 2016 - July. 2015

• Created a web application with an authentication system.

Extra-Curricular Activities

2016-17 Placement Representative, B. Tech CSE - B

2016 **Tech{know}logy Club**, Conducted a workshop on *Introduction to Open Source and git*

2015 Anokha 2k15, worked in the Public Relations Department

2011-13 **School Pupil Leader (SPL) and Asst. SPL**, Kendriya Vidyalaya - IIT Madras

2010 Rajya Puraskar Scout, attended the 16th National Jamboree

Hobbies and Interest

Reading Comics and Manga, Watching Anime, Playing the Piano, Basket Ball, Cycling

Mukesh Arambakam